Lilian de Greef

Seattle, WA 98195 Idegreef@uw.edu www.ldegreef.com

SUMMARY

I am a PhD student at the University of Washington with an NSF fellowship and Microsoft Research PhD fellowship, advised by Shwetak Patel in the Ubiquitous Computing Lab. Within the broad spectrum of ubiquitous computing, my interests include computer vision, embedded systems, machine learning, and HCI. My current research focuses on lowering the access barrier to medical care, using low cost commodity hardware with trained image analysis and innovative user interface design.

EDUCATION

University of Washington (2012 – present)

Ph.D. Student, Computer Science Area: Ubiquitous Computing Advisor: Dr. Shwetak Patel

Harvey Mudd College (2008 – 2012) Bachelor of Science, Computer Science Graduated with distinction

GPA: 3.6/4.0

SKILLS

Programming: Python, C++, OpenCV, Java, Arduino, SystemVerilog, Objective-C, C#,

Scheme, Prolog, ROS

Software: SolidWorks, Autodesk Inventor,

Photoshop, Autodesk 3DS Max

Hardware: 3D printing, laser cutting, fabrication for eTextiles, machining for metal and wood

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Graduate Research, University of Washington

Advisor: Shwetak Patel

Currently investigating how to use smartphone cameras to screen newborns for dangerous levels of jaundice, or yellowing of the skin, in close collaboration with UW Medical Center. Developed data collection procedures and software, applying computer vision to parse images, and using machine learning to estimate jaundice levels. Work thus far has resulted in two publications (one awarded as <u>best paper nominee</u>), two patents, and commercial development.

Research Intern, Microsoft Research Redmond

6/2015 – 9/2015

9/2012 - present

Manager: Merrie Morris

Conceived and developed a prototype of TeleTourist, a system that uses video calls with strangers to share experiences for people with mobility restrictions. Interviewed individuals with mobility restrictions as formative work, designed system features, and implemented a subset of them for a prototype. Presented the work as a poster at CSCW 2016 and resulted in a patent.

Research Science Intern, Amazon

6/2014 - 9/2014

Manager: Jim Curlander

Designed, developed, and evaluated eyes and head tracking based user interface elements for enhanced reality interfaces in fulfillment centers. Combined concepts from computer graphics with HCI Produced several prototypes, demonstrated the system in its intended environment. Resulted in a <u>patent</u>.

Microsoft Computer Science Clinic, Harvey Mudd College

9/2011 - 5/2012

Faculty Advisor: Z Sweedyk Microsoft Liaison: Cati Boulanger

Designed and developed technology to motivate and assess rehabilitation for stroke patients affected in their upper extremities, using the Microsoft Surface in team of four. Interviewed stroke patients and physical therapists, designed a rehabilitative game played on the Microsoft Surface, produced a prototype, and ran user study with stroke patients.